Guide to the Printmaker File [1730]-2014, undated (bulk 1800-1860) PR 58
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Prints 16 x 20" and smaller, 111472
  - Moskowitz, Ira (1912-2001), 111582
    - 4 etching: [A Day in Central Park], [Brooklyn in Winter], Central Park, Long Island Countryside, 1920's, undated; 111583 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
      etchings
  - Murphy, Bill (b. 1952), 20761
    - From Silver Lake (34/50), 1999; 20762 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
  - Nelson, George Laurence (1887-1978), 111580
    - [Still life], 1942; 111581 (Box "N", Folder unknown container)
      lithograph presented to members of the Allied Artists of America
  - Newton, Edith (1878-1964), 111578
    - "Marion's Dolls", 1937; 111579 (Box "N", Folder unknown container)
  - Noual, J. (fl. 1761 to ca. 1790s), 111576
    - "A View of Bethlehem, one of the Brethren's Principal Settlements, in Pennsylvania, North America,", undated; 111577 (Box "N", Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored line engraving after Nathaniel Garrison, printed for Robert Sayer, London
  - Northcote, Stafford M., 111574
    - "Tong Yin Yee Schung Gun", undated; 111575 (Box "N", Folder unknown container)
      proof wood engraving, after his own design, printed on tissue
  - Opper, Frederick Burr (1857-1937), 204792
    - A Hint to the Hebrews- how they may make themselves independent of the watering place hotels, 1881; 204793 (Box "O", Folder unknown container)
      color lithograph cartoon from Puck, (11 May 1881. p.178)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
      gift of Eric Zafran, 2016
  - Pantell, Richard (b. 1927), 20757
    - The Five Points, 1985; 20760 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Valentine Avenue, 1984; 20759 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Wishing Well, artist's proof, 1980; 20758 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Parish, Betty Waldo (1908-1996), 20742
    - Bleecker Street, 1938; 20756 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Doyer Street (3/10), 1936; 20755 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      etching and engraving
    - East of Gramercy (3/19), 1951; 20754 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Encroachment of a City (8/25), 1952; 20753 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      copper engraving
    - 14th Street & 5th Avenue, 1936; 20752 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Gay Street (12/22), 1937; 20751 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Grove and Bedford, 1937; 20750 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Marketing on Avenue A, 1936; 20749 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - The Park from the Plaza (6/23), 1946; 20748 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      etching, engraving, and aquatint
    - Remembrance of Things Past (4/25), 1953; 20747 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Third Avenue and 11th Street (13/20), 1936; 20746 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Thompson Street, 1938; 20745 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - 2 West 15th St., 1950; 20744 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Washington Square South (11/31), 1939; 20743 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Patterson, Charles Robert (1878-1958), 20740
    - Ship "Bangalore" at South St., 1898, 1948; 20741 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Pendleton's Lithography, William S. and John B. Pendelton, 111571
    - "The Toilet", undated; 111573 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - "Henry Costar's Hat Warehouse", 1831; 111572 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      drawn by A. J. Davis
  - Pennell, Joseph (1857-1926), 20736
    - Fifth Avenue Building, undated; 20737 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - [Streetscape], undated; 111570 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      See also: Series II
  - Perard, Victor (1870-1957), 20733
    - Looking Up Broadway New York From No. 1 B'way, 1909; 20735 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - The Old Hansom Cab, 1904; 20734 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      soft ground etching
    - "Sketch Class, Provincetown Mass.", 1940; 111568 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - "Tending Nets, Cape Cod Mass.", 1941; 111567 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Petrulis, Alan (b. 1954), 20730
    - City of Ships (30/100), undated; 20732 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - White Street (30/100), 1977; 20731 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Platt, C.A. (1861-1933), 20728
    - Shanties on the Harlem, [1880]; 20729 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Platt, Peter, J., 20725
    - King Bridge, N.Y., 1917; 20727 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
      after a painting by C. A. Platt, 1884
    - Old Lorillard Snuff Mill, Bronx River, 1912; 20726 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Plowman, George T. (1869-1932), 20720
    - Capt. Adrian Van Brunt Homestead, Brooklyn N.Y. (3/50), undated; 20724 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Capt. Jan Schenck Homestead, Brooklyn N.Y. (3/50), undated; 20723 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Lefferts Homestead (3/50), undated; 20722 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
    - Wyckoff Homestead, Brooklyn, N.Y. (3/50), undated; 20721 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Prang, Louis (1824-1909), 111561
    Includes lithographs after Winslow Homer, from Campaign Sketches, 1863
    - "The Letter for Home", 111565 (Box P, Folder unknown container)
    - "Foraging", 111564 (Box P, Folder unknown container)
    - "Our Jolly Cook", 111563 (Box P, Folder unknown container)
  - Price, Chester B. (1885-1962), 20718
    - Manhattan Forum, undated; 20719 (Box "P", Folder unknown container)
  - Quinlan, Will J. (1877-1919), 20716
    - Fulton Street, 1923; 20717 (Box "Q", Folder unknown container)
  - Raskin, Joseph (1897-1981), 111545
    - "Amherst College", undated; 111560 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Blair Hall, Princeton University", undated; 111559 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Campbell Hall, Princeton University", undated; 111558 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Chapel, Amherst College", undated; 111557 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Chapin Hall, Williams College", undated; 111556 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Converse Hall, Amherst College", undated; 111555 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Griffin Hall, Williams College", undated; 111554 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Memorial Hall, Harvard University", undated; 111553 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Princeton University", undated; 111552 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Rotunda," University of Virginia", undated; 111551 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Serpentine Wall, University of Virginia", undated; 111550 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Sever Hall, Harvard University", undated; 111549 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "West College, Williams College", undated; 111548 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "West Lawn, University of Virginia", undated; 111547 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "Widener Library, Harvard University", undated; 111546 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
  - Reid, Andrew, 20714
    - Grand Central, undated; 20715 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
  - Reisman, Philip (1904-1992), 20701
    - Builders I (60/100), 1928; 20713 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Builders II (99/100), 1928; 20712 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Fruit Wagon (23/100), 1929; 20711 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - The Knife Grinder (38/100), 1929; 20710 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - The Meeting (27/100), 1930; 20709 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Moving Day (26/100), 1929; 20708 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Neighborhood Park (33/100), 1929; 20707 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Peddler (34/100), 1928; 20706 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Peddlers Under the 'L' (37/100), 1928; 20705 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Pershing Square (75/100), undated; 20704 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Soda Fountain (42/100), 1928; 20703 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - Veterans - World War I (40/100), 1931; 20702 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
  - Revere, Paul (1735-1818), 111543
    - "The Bloody Massacre Perpetrated in King Street Boston on March 5th 1770...,", 111544 (Box Revere, Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored engraving
  - Roth, Ernest D. (1879-1964), 20699
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y., 1935; 20700 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - "The South Side of the Inn at Buck Hill Falls", 1940; 111542 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
      published by Buck Hill Art Association
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph (1883-1978), 20696
    - [St. John's Chapel, 40 Varick St.] (33/75), 1911; 20698 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
    - [Clapboard house overlooking river], [1909]; 20697 (Box "R", Folder unknown container)
  - Sabin, Joseph F. (1846-1926), 20694
    - [New York Produce Exchange from Castle Garden], ca. 1895; 20695 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Sartain, John (1808-1897), 111539
    - "Common Deer", 1830; 111540 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored line engraving after Thomas Doughty (1793-1856). Plate One from The Cabinet of Natural History and American Rural Sports: with Illustrations (Philadelphia: J & T. Doughty, 1830.)
  - Schmidt, Louis, 20692
    - Mountains [Hanover Square], 1929; 20693 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Schumann, Karl, 20690
    - Temples Old and New, undated; 20691 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Schutz, Anton (1894-1977), 20685
    - [East River Bridges], undated; 20689 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - 544 Hotel Waldorf Astoria, undated; 20688 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - George Washington Bridge (96/100), undated; 20687 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - Madison Square, undated; 20686 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Shaner?, W., 111803
    - [Dewey Arch], undated; 111804 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Sharp, William (1900-1961), 20682
    - Spanish Quarter, New York (5/50), undated; 20684 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - Third Avenue Nocturne, undated; 20683 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Shaw, Robert (1859-1912), 20680
    - Fraunces Tavern, New York, printed for members of the Colonial Society of America, [1906]; 20681 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Smith, Wuanita (1866-1959), 20678
    - Columbus Jewels, undated; 20679 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Soyer, Raphael (1899-1987), 114582
    - The Artist's Parents, ca. 1963; 114583 (Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Steeden, O., 111528
    Includes plates from Illustrations to Knickerbocker's History of New York (London: T. Palser, 1830) all engraved after Steeden's own design.
    - "Governor Stuyvesant Resolves to Defend his Horse", 111538 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "Dedrick Knickerbocker Chiding his Landlady for settling his room to rights", 111537 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "Squatters Arriving at a Fresh Settlement", 111536 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "Van Twiller and Council Met in Debate", 111535 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "The renowned Van Corlear, the Dutch Trumpeter", 111534 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Four Great Dutch Characters, Van Zant, Hardenbrock, Ten Broeken, and Van Courtland", 111533 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "Negro Servant Relating Tales to the Settlers", 111532 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "Dutch Cobbler Haranguing the Mob", 111531 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
    - "Farm Yard Melody, or the Dutch Settler's Glory", 111530 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Stokes, Caroline Phelps (1854-1909), 20676
    - [Residence of Anson Greene Phelps, East River and 30th], undated; 20677 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Sturges, Dwight Case (1874-1940), 20674
    - #1 Broadway, after 1921; 20675 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
  - Sumner, H. F. & Co., 111525
    - "Eleanor", 1833; 111527 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored, drawn by J. Penniman
    - "The Love Letter", 1833; 111526 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
      drawn by J. Penniman
  - Szanto, Lajos (Louis) (1889-1965), 204644
    - News boys, Wall Street, ca. 1935; 204645 (Box "S", Folder unknown container)
      etching and drypoint
  - Thienny?, G. A., 111523
    - [Snow scene, with bridge over creek], undated; 111524 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
  - Tittle, Walter Ernest (1883-1966), 20672
    - Manhattan Minarets, undated; 20673 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
  - Trowbridge, Vaughan (1869-1945), 20670
    - [London Terrace], undated; 20671 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
      color etching
  - Trueblood, Emily (b. 1942), 20665
    - City Towers (2/50), 1994; 20669 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
      linocut
    - Night Tower(31/50), 2000; 20668 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
    - Rooftop View 1 (16/50), 2000; 20667 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
      woodcut
    - World Trade View (31/50), 1995; 20666 (Box "T", Folder unknown container)
  - Vanderhook, ?, 20663
    - St. John the Divine, undated; 20664 (Box "V", Folder unknown container)
  - Van Notti, Henry (1878-1962), 20660
    - Barclay St., New York, [1915]; 20662 (Box "V", Folder unknown container)
    - New and Old New York, [1910]; 20661 (Box "V", Folder unknown container)
  - Walcot, William (1874-1943), 20658
    - Brooklyn Bridge, [1920]; 20659 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Walker, Steven (b. 1955), 20656
    - Sunset Skyline, 1999; 20657 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Wall, Bernhardt (1872-1956), 20653
    - Italian Church on Minetta Lane, 1918; 20655 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Ten Etchings of Greenwich Village Landmarks in the War Year of 1918, 1947; 20654 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      bound booklet
  - Wallace, William H., 20638
    - "Along the Hackensack", undated; 111522 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Ann Street, corner Theatre Alley, undated; 20652 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Bradburns Bookstall, undated; 20651 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Clean-Drinking Manor House, Maryland", undated; 111521 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - The Burdell House at 31 Bond Street, undated; 20650 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Fog Under Bridge Tower, 1882; 20649 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Fulton Street [(Brooklyn) Between Johnson and Myrtle Ave East Side], 1845; 20648 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Grape Vine Inn; Last of the Shades], undated; 20647 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Harlem River in 1870, 20646 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      2 copies, different sizes
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), 1882; 20645 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), 1882; 20644 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (2nd state), 1882; 20643 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [New York from Staten Island (?)], 1890; 20642 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Old New York, undated; 20641 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Old School house, Tuckahoe Rd., Mt. Vernon", 1881; 111520 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], 1888; 20640 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Prison of Major Andre", undated; 111519 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], undated; 20639 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Trees at Demorest", undated; 111518 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Waller, Frank (1842-1923), 20636
    - [Museum interior], 1893; 20637 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Ward, Caleb, 111515
    - "View of the Spot where Gen. Hamilton fell at Weehawk [with a View of New York]", 1830; 111516 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      Hand-colored aquatint after Jacob C. Ward, date depicted 1806.
  - Ward, Lynd (1905-1985), 20634
    - Under the El, undated; 20635 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Werger, Art (b.1955), 20630
    - Attraction, 2003; 20633 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      mezzotint
    - Daybreak (56/75), 1997; 20632 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Early Thaw (72/75), 1996; 20631 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Whistler, James Abbott McNeill (1834-1903), 111501
    "Twelve Etchings from Nature," printed in Paris, published in London by James A. Whistler, 1858, in original wrapper
    - "Liverdun", 111514 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "La Retameuse", 111513 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "En Plein Soleil", 111512 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Unsafe Tenement", 111511 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "La Mere Gerard", 111510 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Street at Saverne", 111509 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Little Arthur", 111508 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "La Vielle aux Loques", 111507 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Annie", 111506 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "La Marchande de Moutarde", 111505 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Fumette", 111504 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Kitchen", 111503 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - White, Charles Henry (1878-1918), 20618
    - Bit of Bleecker St. (3/10), 1903; 20629 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Bleecker St. Gables, N.Y., 1903; 20628 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Boiler Works [David M. Nichols Boiler Works], 1902; 20627 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - East River Bridge II, 1903; 20626 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Five Points, N.Y., undated; 20625 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Hudson Street (16/25), undated; 20624 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Mulberry Bend, N.Y., 1903; 20623 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Old Warf II, Third State, undated; 20622 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Shipsmith and blacksmith shop], undated; 20621 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - The Tenement, Third State, 1903; 20620 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Thompson Street Inn, Fifth State, undated; 20619 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Whitefield, Edwin (1816-1892), 111499
    - "Lobelia Syphilitica", undated; 111500 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored lithograph by Lewis & Brown, New York, after drawings by Whitefield, illustration from Emma C. Embury's American Wild Flowers in Their Native Haunts (New York: D. Appleton & Co., 1845)
  - Wilbur, Lawrence Nelson (1897-1988), 20607
    - Along the Docks (5/50), [1945]; 20617 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      after his watercolor
    - The East River, 1946; 20616 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Manhattan Mountains, 1938; 20615 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Old Brownstones - New York (16/50), 1923; 20614 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Peck's Slip - N.Y.C. (proof), 1938; 20613 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - September- Central Park (32/50), undated; 20612 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), undated; 20611 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Under the Bridge (6/27), 1988; 20610 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (7/75), 1976; 20609 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (9/75), 1976; 20608 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Wolchonok, Louis (1898-1973), 20593
    - Bridge, Sheepshead Bay (71/150), undated; 20606 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Fort Lee Ferry (28/150), undated; 20605 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Fourteenth Street, undated; 20604 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Hellgate Bridge (1/150), undated; 20603 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [New York Telephone and Telegraph Building] (25/150), undated; 20602 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Saint Paul's], undated; 20601 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Sheepshead Bay] (40/150), undated; 20600 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Spring in Central Park], undated; 20599 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Street Construction, New York] (7/150), undated; 20598 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - Subway Construction at 8th Ave. and 116th St., 1926; 20597 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Riverside Park with bridge] (1st proof, 2nd state), undated; 20596 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - [Weber Coal Company], undated; 20595 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      [Attributed]
    - [Woolworth Building], undated; 20594 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Wolf, Henry (1852-1916), 111497
    - [Woman with two children], undated; 111498 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      Inscribed to Samuel Shaw from Abbott Handerson Thayer (1849-1921)
  - Woodruff, Hale (1900-1980), 111488
    - "African Headdress", 111496 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "By Parties Unknown", 111495 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Coming Home", 111494 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Giddap", 111493 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Old Church", 111492 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Relics", 111491 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Sunday Promenade", 111490 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
    - "Trusty on a Mule", 111489 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
      Portfolio, 156 of 300, all linocuts dating from 1931-1940, printed in 1996
  - Woodcut Society, wood engravings published by, 111479
    - Buckland-Wright, John, 1897-1954, "The Forest Pool, 1939; 111487 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Cheffetz, Asa, 1896-1965, "Midsummer Vermont", 1936; 111486 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Cheffetz, Asa, 1896-1965, "Down Montgomery Way (Vermont)", 1940; 111485 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Cook, Howard Norton, 1901-1980, "Eagle Dance", 1942; 111484 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Landacre, Paul, 1893-1963, "Black Stallion, undated; 111483 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Lathrop, Dorothy P. "Kou Hsiung", 1944; 111482 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Leighton, Clare, b. 1899, "Winnowers Majorca", 1939; 111481 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Lindsay, Lionel, b. 1874, "Repose", 1938; 111480 (Box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
  - Wortsman, Harold, 111477
    - "A new form of skywriting", undated; 111478 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Wyllie, William L. (1851-1931), 111475
    - [Ship in New York Harbor, with tugboats], ca. 1895-1903; 111476 (Box "W", Folder unknown container)
  - Zabriskie, George A. (1868-1954), 111473
    - Ten untitled prints, undated; 111474 (Box "Z", Folder unknown container)
- Series II: Prints 16 x 20" to 30 x 40", 111340
  Series II. Prints 16 x 20" to 30 x 40," is also filed by artist or printmaker's surname. The prints are are housed in drawers in flat files. This series contains many important eighteenth-century prints, particularly views of New York City.
  Three of Karl Akrell's engravings after Axel Leonhard Klinckowstrom are from Klinckowstrom's Atlas, which was published in Sweden in 1824. A complete copy of this early work is also held by the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections. The view of City Hall is notable for the pigs shown prominently in the foreground.